



CONTACT

Mobile	(972) 567-5105
Email	mac_hopper@mac.com

LINKS



www.macauleyhopper.com



www.linkedin.com/in/machopper

Personal Statement

I love production, they help the culmination of so many different talented people from artists, to musicians, to actors and beyond. Seeing all aspects come together to create a finished product is an amazing and rewarding experience. In my spare time I like attending local meetups and talking with other people in the industry. Creative work is a huge aspect of my life, helping craft unique and engaging works for viewers that they will continue to talk about for years to come.

Professional Experience

2018

Digital Producer - Contract

Cactex Media, Dallas, TX - October 2018 - December 2018

- \bullet Created detailed timelines, wire frames, menu mockups, and wire layouts
- Kept track of multiple applications requirements
- Worked with stakeholders to ensure projects met their company needs
- Worked with a team and stakeholders to stay on schedule and solve any and all roadblocks
- Developed storyboards for video and demos

Configuration Management Engineer

XO Communications, Plano, TX - October 2014 - March 2018

- $\bullet \ \mathsf{Created} \ \mathsf{documentation} \ \mathsf{for} \ \mathsf{various} \ \mathsf{applications}, \mathsf{including} \ \mathsf{Git}, \mathsf{SourceTree}, \mathsf{Tortoise} \ \mathsf{Git}, \mathsf{and} \ \mathsf{Team} \ \mathsf{Foundation} \ \mathsf{Server}.$
- Managed Agile development process, hosting daily scrums with 10 developers.
- Provided support for Git development tool and build environments

Personal Projects

Current

Producer & Designer - A.R.C.H.O.N

Tiny Tyrants, Plano, TX - January 2015 - Present

- $\bullet \ \ \text{Designed the destructible environment mechanic, event card system, and all armor and we apons.}$
- Studied and maintained target demographic studies for optimal customer reach.
- Led play testing sessions, and designed and balanced the armor and weapon systems
- 2011

Producer & Designer - Five Suns

Studio Hue, Savannah, GA - January 2014 - June 2014

• Designed the moment-to-moment gameplay, including the combat system, enemy classes, and spell sets.

 $\bullet \ Collaborated \ with \ artists \ to \ ensure \ the \ armor \ pieces \ and \ we apons \ were \ able \ to \ work \ with \ the \ players' \ ARCHON \ cards.$

- Led play testing and daily scrum sessions, and oversaw cast and crew production schedule.
- $\bullet \ Presented \ results \ of \ the \ play \ testing \ sessions \ to \ various \ departmental \ personnel.$
- Directly responsible for all project deadlines, including all art assets, design principals, voice work, and casting.
- Received Entelechy 2014 Best 2D Game Award.



Producer & Designer - Vallo

Savannah College of Art and Design, Savannah, GA - September 2013 - November 2013

- Designed a RTS RPG Tower Defense game
- $\bullet \, \text{Worked with 2 freelance artists to help create concept art for the project} \\$
- Producer & Designer Flight of the Meridian

Savannah College of Art and Design, Savannah, GA - September 2013 - November 2013

- Designed a 3 versus 1 board game
- Worked with 2 freelance artists to help create concept art for the project

EDUCATION



Savannah, College of Art and Design, Savannah GA Bachelor of Fine Arts in Interactive Design and Game Development 2014

SOFTWARE

Autodesk Maya
Unreal Development Kit
Adobe Creative Suite
Google Product Suite
Jira
Team Foundation Server
Git
Microsoft Office